A furry tale about me.
The Amazing Maurice is a animation, adventure,
comedy film directed by Toby Genkel.
Maurice is a streetwise ginger cat who comes up with a money-making
scam by befriending a group of self-taught talking rats.
When Maurice and the rodents meet a bookworm called Malicia,
their little con soon goes down the drain.
Maurice (voice), played by Hugh Laurie.
Malicia (voice), played by Emilia Clarke.
Boss Man / Rat King (voice), played by David Thewlis.
Keith (voice), played by Himesh Patel.
Dangerous Beans (voice), played by David Tennant.
Peaches (voice), played by Gemma Arterton.
The Amazing Maurice is a 2022 animated fantasy comedy film directed by Toby Genkel and co-directed by Florian Westermann, from a
screenplay by Terry Rossio, based on the 2001 novel The Amazing Maurice and His Educated Rodents by Terry Pratchett.
The film stars Hugh Laurie, Emilia Clarke, David Thewlis, Himesh Patel, Gemma Arterton, Joe
Sugg, Ariyon Bakare, Julie Atherton, Rob Brydon, Hugh Bonneville and David Tennant.
The story follows Maurice, a streetwise ginger cat who befriends the
talking rats by coming up with a money-making scam.
An animated film adaptation of Pratchett's novel was announced in
June 2019, with Rossio writing the screenplay.
Most of the lead cast members were hired in November 2020,
with additional cast being added in May 2021.
Animation was provided by Studio Rakete and Red Star 3D.
The Amazing Maurice had its premiere at the Manchester Animation Festival on 13 November
2022, and was released in the United Kingdom on 16 December, by Sky Cinema.
It was released on 3 February 2023 by Viva Pictures in the United States.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, grim
reaper, cartoon cat, nine lives, rat.
The tone is lighthearted.